Kiran Methuku

Full Stack Web Developer

San Jose, CA (408) 431-9732 kmethuku@protonmail.com (7) /kmethuku

in /kiranmethuku0831 kiranmethuku.com

PROFILE

I'm a web developer with a user-driven mindset. I design and build applications that are engaging and intuitive to navigate. Above all, I believe in delivering value continuously by shipping fast, quality code. On top of my technical skills, I have experience in market research, project management, and client relations.

SKILLS

Koa JavaScript/TypeScript React Redux **Express** Node **PostgreSQL**

BEM CSS GraphQL Git Mocha Sequelize MongoDB Mongoose Jest

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer. Fitome 🗆

2021 - present

- Designed, developed, and deployed Fitome with a distributed Agile team of 4 developers using React, Redux, Node.js, and PostgreSQL
- Configured PWA service worker to handle client-side caching and offline access with Google Workbox
- Implemented state management and handled asynchronous operations with Redux
- Designed and built an extensive relational database using PostgreSQL with Sequelize
- Set up MVC-compliant RESTful API optimized to reduce network load

Full Stack Developer, Cardshare

2021 - present

- Designed, developed, and deployed Cardshare as solo developer using React, Node.js, and MongoDB
- Implemented search logic using JSON data fetched via Google Books API
- Implemented authentication and authorization with Firebase
- Crafted a seamless and responsive cross-platform compatible UI using BEM CSS
- Set up MVC-compliant RESTful API with Express and MongoDB

Project Manager & Consultant, The MarkeTech Group ☑

• Managed multinational market research projects for Fortune 500 clients

November 2018 -November 2019

EDUCATION

Quantitative Psychology B.S., University of California Davis

2015 - 2017

CS Courses: C++, Data Structures

Software Engineering Immersive, Codeworks

2021

Full Stack Web Development

REFERENCES

Christian Renaudin, CEO & Founder, The MarkeTech Group crenaudin@themarketechgroup.com, (530) 792-8400 x302